Guide to the Washington State University / United States Department of Agriculture Cooperative Projects Reports 1931-1971
Washington State University Libraries Manuscripts, Archives, and Special Collections
Washington State University / United States Department of Agriculture Cooperative Projects Reports
1931-1971
Washington State University Libraries, Manuscripts, Archives and Special Collections
Archives 259
2 Linear feet of Shelf Space 2 boxes
Beginning in 1931, the United States Department of Agriculture began cooperative studies with the State College of Washington. Cooperative research projects have involved matters such as the development of plant varieties, control of plant diseases, control of weeds, and the production of seeds. In the years from 1931 to 1970, attention focused on cereals, especially wheat. Some investigations involved grasses.
Beginning in 1931, the United States Department of Agriculture began cooperative studies with the State College of Washington. Projects covered cereal improvements, cereal diseases, noxious weed investigations, and seed production investigations. Notable individuals involved in the projects were Orville Vogel, C.S. Holton, C.I. Seely, Robert Allan, and W.C. Robocker.
Cooperative research projects have involved matters such as the development of plant varieties, control of plant diseases, control of weeds, and the production of seeds. In the years from 1931 to 1970, attention focused on cereals, especially wheat. Some investigations involved grasses.
Annual reports of cooperative research projects summarize activities and typically are bound in book form.
The reports are arranged by their topic of investigation and author placed in chronological order. A few individual reports, some of which are USDA projects, but not necessarily in collaboration with the State College of Washington, are placed at the end of the sequence.
This collection is open and available for research use.
Reports of the cooperative projects between the State College of Washington and the United States Department of Agriculture were accessioned by the Washington State University Libraries in 1988 (UA88-01).
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Vogel, Orville Alvin, 1907-1991.; Holton, Charles Stewart, 1904-; Seely, C. I. (Clarence Ivan), 1912-; Allan, Robert E., 1931-; Robocker, Willard Charles, 1915-1999.
Washington State University; State College of Washington; United States. Department of Agriculture.
Crop improvement -- United States; Crops -- Disease and pest resistance -- United States; Weeds -- Control -- United States
Agriculture
  - Cereal Improvement, Annual Report. (Orville Vogel, Joseph Craddock, Clarence Peterson)
    - 1931 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - 1932 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - 1933 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - 1934 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 1935 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - 1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - 1937 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - 1938 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - 1941 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - 1942 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - 1943 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - 1945 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - 1946 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - 1947 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - 1948 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - 1950 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - 1951 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - 1952 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - 1953 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - 1954 (Box 1, Folder 22)
    - 1955 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - 1956 (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - 1957 (Box 1, Folder 25)
    - 1969 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Investigations on Wheat Bunt and Oat Smuts, Annual Report. (C.S. Holton)
    - 1933 (Box 1, Folder 27)
    - 1934 (Box 1, Folder 28)
    - 1935 (Box 1, Folder 29)
    - 1936 (Box 1, Folder 30)
    - 1937 (Box 1, Folder 31)
    - 1938 (Box 1, Folder 32)
    - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 33)
    - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 34)
    - 1942 (Box 1, Folder 35)
    - 1943 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Bunt and Smut Resistance in Wheat and Oats, Annual Report. (E.F. Gaines)
    - 1934 (Box 1, Folder 37)
    - 1935 (Box 1, Folder 38)
    - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Noxious Weed Investigations, Annual Report. (C.I. Seely)
    - 1936 (Box 1, Folder 40)
    - 1937 (Box 1, Folder 41)
    - 1938 (Box 1, Folder 42)
    - 1939 (Box 1, Folder 43)
    - 1940 (Box 1, Folder 44)
    - 1941 (Box 1, Folder 45)
    - 1942 (Box 1, Folder 46)
    - 1943 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Forage Report, Washington Agronomic Data
    - 1955 (Box 2, Folder 48)
    - 1956 (Box 2, Folder 48)
  - Cereal Improvement, Annual Report. (Robert Allan)
    - 1958 (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - 1967 (Box 2, Folder 51)
    - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 52)
  - Weed Control in Grazing and Non-Crop Lands, Annual Report. (W.C. Robocker, H.D. Kerr, R.D. Schirman)
    - 1958 (Box 2, Folder 53)
    - 1959 (Box 2, Folder 54)
    - 1965 (Box 2, Folder 55)
    - 1966 (Box 2, Folder 56)
    - 1968 (Box 2, Folder 57)
    - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 58)
    - 1971 (Box 2, Folder 59)
  - Grass Seed Production Investigations, Annual Report. (C.L Canode, E.V. Horning)
    - 1959 (Box 2, Folder 60)
    - 1965 (Box 2, Folder 61)
    - 1966 (Box 2, Folder 62)
    - 1968 (Box 2, Folder 63)
    - 1969 (Box 2, Folder 64)
    - 1970 (Box 2, Folder 65)
  - Other Reports
    - Weed Control Investigations, Summary Annual Reports, Arizona-Idaho-Montana-Utah-Washington, 1953. (Box 2, Folder 66)
    - Agricultural Stabilization and Conservation, Annual Statistical Report, Washington State, 1954-1958. (Box 2, Folder 67)
    - Cereal Improvement, Annual Report, 1955. (Everett Everson) (Box 2, Folder 68)
    - Western 2-Row Barley Nursery and Rocky Mountain Barley Nursery, Progress Report, 1970. (E.A. Hockett) (Box 2, Folder 69)
    - Results from Cooperative Wheat Experiments in the Western Region, Progress Report, 1970. (F.H. McNeal) (Box 2, Folder 70)